

About Me

Compassionate and dedicated Registered Nurse with six and a half years post-graduation experience in general and orthopedic med/Surg, and spinal cord injuries and disease. I am currently working with spinal injuries and disease patients at the VA Medical Center here in Syracuse. I am interested in joining your floor. Looking forward to hearing from you.

Contact

- 315 870 4286
- nyantiok.manas@yahoo.com
- 203 Berkshire Ave., Syracuse NY 13208

⟨☼⟩ Skills

- Wound dressing and care, including ostomies, fistula, and tracheostomy.
- Supervise and monitor patients on respiratory equipment, Ventilators, BiPAP/CPAP, non-rebreather, or highflow oxygen.
- Inserted/removed catheters and irrigations.
- MONITOR AND TRACK MEDICAL TUBE/DRAINAGE SYSTEMS: NEPHROSTOMY TUBE, CHEST TUBE, WOUND VOC, JP DRAIN,

At LANGUAGES



Nyantiok Manas W. Bul

Registered Nurse (RN)

Education

(2023 - present)
CHAMBERLIAN UNIVERSITY, COLLEGE OF PUBLIC HEALTH
master of Public Health

(2022 - 2023)
CHAMBERLIAN UNIVERSITY
COLLEGE OF SCIENCE IN NURSING
Bachelor of Nursing

² (2015 – 2018)

ST. JOSEPH'S COLLEGE OF NURSING

Associate in Applied Science Registered Nursing (RN)

(2009 – 2010)

TBRILLIANT INSTITUTE OF PROFESSIONAL STUDIES
DIPLOMA IN COMPUTING AND INFORMATION SYSTEMS

Certifications

- REGISTERED NURSE IN THE STATE OF NEW YORK
- BLS AND AED AT VA MEDICAL CENTER
- ACLS CERTIFIED AT VA MEDICAL CENTER

Honoree and Awards

- DR. ROBERT CORSKY SCHOLARSHIP AWARDS
- PHI THETA KAPPA HONOR SOCIETY
- MEMBER OF THE HONORS PROGRAM AT SUNY ONONDAGA COMMUNITY COLLEG
- TWO CERTIFICATES OF ACADEMIC ACHIEVEMENTS

WORK EXPERIENCE

spinal cord injuries and disease SCI/D

St. Joseph's Hospital

2023 - Present

- · Ventilator care and management.
- Wound vac placement, ostomy care, and management, suprapubic placement, and management.
- Complex wound dressing and care.
- · Lower Limp Amputees gait training and rehabilitation.
- injectable and oral chemotherapy administration and cancer patient care and management.

RN Orthopedic Med/Surg 6C

VA at Syracuse, NY.

2020 - 2023.

- Team/Charge Nurse, assigning patients to nurses on the floor, making assignments ready for the next shift.
- Doing unit audits and checking emergency charts for rapid/code blue checks.
- The go-to person for IV and blood draws on complex patients.
- Well-trained in peritoneal dialysis, PICC, and port line management.
- Priorities patient and staff safety by using different types of ambulation equipment.
- · Mentor and percept new staff.

RN Med/Surg

St. Joseph's Hospital Health Center, Syracuse, NY.

2018-2020

- Monitor and communicate patients' health status/changes with interdisciplinary
 toams.
- Educate patients and families about patient care in the hospital and at home for a safe discharge and to minimize readmission risk.
- Functioned in a leadership role as team leader/charge nurse; assigned patients and monitored care delivered by RN, LPN, and Student Nurse Aide.
- Participated in St. Joseph's Health pain and pain treatment committee.

Teacher Assistant

St. Vincent de Paul daycare, Syracuse, NY.

2013 - 2014

- supervision of children from three months to eight years old.
- Monitoring children in the schoolyard and assisting with homework.

Student nurse aide

St. Joseph's Hospital Health Center, Syracuse, NY.

2017 - 2018.

- Bedside care, meal setup, and assisting patients with ambulation.
- Takes Vital signs and reports abnormal critical to RN.

References

- Mary H. Ryan, St. Joseph's College of Nursing (315) 448 5671, maryh.ryan@sjhsyr.org
- Christiana Okereke.
 (315) 558 9227 <u>Christiana.Okereke@va.gov</u>
- Verna Steward
 (315) 420 7993 <u>Verne.Steward@va,gov</u>
- Ruth Omonduki. VA medical center (315) 391 7539, <u>Ruth.Omonduki@va.gov</u>